

MASTER'S STUDENT IN ROBOTICS

Lerchenrain 13, 8046 Zurich

📕 +41 76 470 25 50 | 🗷 peter@pbreuer.de | 👑 January 21st, 2000 | 😭 pbreuer.de | 🖸 breuerpeter | 🛅 peter-breuer





Summary.

Master's student in robotics, systems and control at ETH Zurich (graduation in Fall 2024). Experience in legged and aerial robotics (sUAS). Primary interest in GNC software engineering for autonomous UAVs. Knowledge in robotics subdomains including computer vision, kinematics and dynamics, path planning, state estimation, model predictive control, and reinforcement learning (neural control policies).

Work Experience __

ETH Zurich Zurich, Switzerland

RESEARCH ASSISTANT AT THE ROBOTIC SYSTEMS LAB (RSL)

- Developed a GUI with RQt for controlling a quadrupedal robot using ROS 2
- Set up a containerized ROS 2 development environment using Docker

RESEARCH ASSISTANT AT THE AUTONOMOUS SYSTEMS LAB (ASL)

· Rapid prototyping of a payload retrieval mechanism for a VTOL UAV using additive manufacturing

Freefly Systems Inc.

Seattle metropolitan area, USA

ROBOTICS SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN

03.2022 - 07.2022

- Created a PX4 flight mode for the industrial drone «Astro» 🗗 enabling precise framing and tracking with a gimbaled camera payload
- Added the possibility to configure a MAVLink-enabled gimbal in the ground control station
- · Created an onboard application with pymavlink to request and publish received distance sensor readings via MAVLink messages
- Proof of concept for an app using MAVSDK to shoot hyperlapses with MAVLink-enabled UAVs

ETH Zurich Zurich, Switzerland

TEACHING ASSISTANT AT THE ENGINEERING DESIGN AND COMPUTING LABORATORY (EDAC)

09.2019 - 12.2021

09.2022 - 12.2023

· Course: Technical Drawing and CAD

TEACHING ASSISTANT AT THE INSTITUTE FOR DYNAMIC SYSTEMS AND CONTROL (IDSC)

• Course: Control Systems I and II

Education _

ETH Zurich Zurich, Switzerland

MSc Robotics, Systems and Control

09/2022 - present

- Semester project: Altitude Estimation for UAV Operations Over Water Integration and Testing of LiDAR and Radar Distance Sensors under the supervision of Dr. Guillaume Ducard at the Institute for Dynamic Systems and Control (IDSC) group of Prof. Onder
- Master's thesis: Autonomous Tracking of Moving Subjects With UAVs Using Deep Reinforcement Learning under the supervision of Jiaxu Xing and Angel Romero at the Robotics and Perception Group (University of Zurich) led by Prof. Davide Scaramuzza

National University of Singapore

Singapore

MSc Semester Exchange Program

01/2023 - 05/2023

ETH Zurich Zurich, Switzerland

BSc Mechanical Engineering

09/2018 - 08/2022

- GPA: 5.5/6.0 (approx. top 4% of 207)
- Student project: *Dyana Dynamic Quadrupedal Animatronic -* A quadrupedal robot developed by an interdisciplinary team of 14 students from multiple Swiss universities. Dyana is capable of dynamic motions and conveys a unique, life-like impression through its feline appearance. The project was hosted by the Robotics System Lab (RSL) led by Prof. Marco Hutter and was supported by several industry sponsors. More info from the roll-out presentation (English subtitles) \(\mathbb{C}\)?
- Bachelor's thesis: Low- and High-Level Control for Testing Single Legs of the Quadrupedal Animatronic Dyana in collaboration with Marco Trentini and under the supervision of Fabian Tischhauser and Marcus Montenegro at the RSL. We developed a ROS 1 (C++) framework for dynamic testing of robotic legs using virtual model- and inverse dynamics control. It allowed us to test the mechanical integrity of the front and hind legs of Dyana in a wall-mounted linear guide rail setup and evaluate the commercially available T-MOTOR AK10-9 actuators used.

Leipzig International School

Leipzig, Germany 08/2016 - 05/2018

INTERNATIONAL BACCALAUREATE (IB) BILLINGUAL DIPLOMA

- Score: 42/45 (top 4.54% worldwide)
- Higher level subjects: Mathematics, Physics, English (B)
- Standard level subjects: Chemistry, Geography, German (A)
- Valedictorian

Leipzig International School

Leipzig, Germany

08/2014 - 06/2016

INTERNATIONAL GENERAL CERTIFICATE OF SECONDARY EDUCATION (IGCSE)

• Top of the year group

Honors & Awards

AWARDS

06/2018 **Duke of Edinburgh's International Silver Award**, Duke of Edinburgh's Award

Leipzig, Germany

10/2016 **Outstanding Cambridge Learner Awards**, Cambridge Assessment International Education

Leipzig, Germany

Skills_

Languages German (native), English (C2), Spanish (A2), Chinese (A1)

Programming Python, C++, C, MATLAB, LaTeX

Robotics ROS 1, ROS 2

UAVs PX4 Autopilot, MAVSDK, MAVLink, Betaflight, QGroundControl

Machine Learning PyTorch, Weights and Biases

Computer Vision OpenCV
Front-End Qt for Python
DevOps Docker, Linux

Hobbies

2019 - Fitness (calisthenics and weight training)

2018 - Backpacking

2012 - Enduro mountain biking

2010 - **Photography**, Portfolio ♂